Business Ephemera Collection
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library
- Trade cards, Business Cards, Miscellaneous Small Advertisements
  - Postcard, Steam Boiler Appliance Company, 189-?; "At The Pratt & Whitney Co." Officers are R. N. Pratt and Ernest Cady. (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Stedman and Company, 185-?; "Foreign and Domestic Fruit, Wood and Willow Ware, Bird Cages of All Descriptions and Styles, Pickles, Preserves, Olive Oil, Sardines, English and French Mustards, Castile Soap, Choice Havana and Principe Cigars." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, T. Steele and Son, 188-?; Partners are Thomas Steele and Thomas S. Steele (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Thomas Steele and Son, 187-?; "Stone Cameos from Life, cut to order and mounted." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Thomas Steele and Son, 1886; Includes calendar for 1887 (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Stern and Hartstall, 185-?; Partners are Myer Stern and Henry Hartstall. (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Stern and Mandelbaum, 185-?; "Successors to Henry W. Katzenberg." Partners are A. Stern and J. Mandelbaum (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Business card, John B. Stewart, Sr., 198-?; Business card of John B. Stewart, Sr. (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Stillman and Company, 188-?; Four different humorous designs featuring children and animals (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Stillman and Company, 188-?; One miniature card featuring the flag of Arabia (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Storrs and Candee, 188-?; "Visit the Toboggan Slide at No. 78 Wethersfield Ave." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade cards, D.G. Stoughton and Company, 1876?; Two copies of card featuring butterflies. "A full line of Drugs, Patent Medicines and Necessities, at Lowest Prices." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, D.E. Strong, 188-?; Two different designs (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, D.E. Strong, 187-?; "Children's Shoes with A.S.T. Co. Black Tips Protecting the Toes." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Strong's, 188-?; Two different designs "Gems of the Seaside" and "Whoa Emma" featuring silhouettes. (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, Strong and Nichols, 186-?; Partners are Julius L. Strong (Late of Welles & Strong) and James Nichols (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, F.C. Sturtevant, 188-?; Successor to Chas. R. Allen & Co. "Will Make Your Hens Lay!" (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Business card, Maureen Sullivan Stemberg, 198-? (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, A.B. Sutherland, 188-?; "Churches, Halls, &c. decorated by experienced artists. Cut Flowers always on hand." (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, A.L. Swift (Box 10, Folder S)
  - Trade card, C.M. Talcott, 185-?; "Paper Hangings, Fire-Board Views, Oil Curtains, Curtain Cornices & Bands, Curtain Trimmings, &c." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, William H. Talcott and Brother, 187-?; "Practical Book Binders and Fist Class Blank Book Manufacturers." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, Talcott and Company, 18--?; One card with picture of "Little Red Riding Hood." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, Tartarine Manufacturing Company, 18--?; Two different designs featuring chimney sweeps (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Postcard, Taylor and Greenough Company, 19--?; Card with "The Star-Spangled Banner" printed on it. (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Postcard, Taylor and Greenough Company, 19--?; Card with "The Star-Spangled Banner" printed on it. (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, Terry and Munson, 186-?; Partners are Roderick Terry and E. S. Munson (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, Charles Teske, 188-?; "Personal Attention Given to Repairing and Adjusting Fine Watches." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, Miss S.G. Theis, 188-?; Printed by Steam Press of A. W. Lang, 96 Asylum Street. (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Brochure, Thirty-six Lewis Street, 197-?; "Once a Victorian Residence, Now Something New." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Appointment card, Tiago Hair Salon, 199-?; Back of card has space for date of "Next Appointment" and name of "Designer." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, A.H. Tillinghast, 187-?; Two different designs featuring autumn leaves (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, A.W. Tracy, 18--?; "Containing a large variety of Books, Stationery and Perfumery of all kinds and of the best quality." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Business card, Travelers Insurance Company, 198-?; Business card of Mark Vereen, Senior Engineering Specialist (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Business card, Tucker, Anthony and R.L. Day, Inc., 1983?; Business card of Robert H. Ritchie (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, E. Tucker's Sons, 197-?; "Straw Boards, Bristol Boards, Chinas, and Blanks, Paper Bags, Twines and Glue." (Box 10, Folder T)
  - Trade card, United States Hotel, 187-?; D. A. Rood, Proprietor. "The Largest and most Centrally Located Hotel in the City." (Box 10, Folder U)
  - Business cards, United Way of the Capital area, 1989?; Business cards of Charles L. Hayes, Vice President, and Courtney W. Gardner, Planning Associate (Box 10, Folder U)
  - Brochure, Veeder Manufacturing Company, 189-?; Description of Veeder Cyclometers for bicycles (Box 10, Folder V)
  - Brochure, Veeder Manufacturing Company, 192-?; Description of Veeder Form C Tachometer (Box 10, Folder V)
  - Appointment book, Veeder Manufacturing Company, 1937; Includes calendars for October-December 1937 and for 1938 (Box 10, Folder V)
  - Trade card, A.D. Vorce Company, 187-?; "Importers of Oil and Water Color Paintings, Artist's Material, Engravings, Etching, &c." Four different designs printed by Bufford, Boston. (Box 10, Folder V)
  - Brochure, A.D. Vorce Company, 187-?; Leaflet with list of works of art for sale (Box 10, Folder V)
  - Trade card, Robert Walker, 188-?; One Oriental design (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Business card, Robert Walker's, 188-?; Location of Fire Boxes on back of card (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Postcard, Walton Company, 1939; Postcard acknowledging receipt of order (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, William Wander and Son, 188-?; Card with girl, harp and shamrocks advertising Estey Organ Co. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, William Wander and Son, 188-?; Seventeen designs advertising Decker, Fischer, Sohmer, and Steinway pianos (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Business card, William Wander and Son, 190-?; Card with portrait of William Wander, "Agent for the Wonderful A. B. Chase Pianos." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Business cards, Ward Interiors, 1984; Two business cards of Jeannette S. Ward, A.S.I.D. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Warner Photograph Company, 190-?; "Finishing for Amateurs" "Bromide Enlargments of all Sizes" (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Notebook, Warwick's, 1935; Blank book with advertising on front and back covers; includes 1935 calendar (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, R.G. Waterous the Hatter and Company, 188-?; Location of Fire Alarm Boxes on back of card (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, R.G. Waterous the Hatter and Company, 187-?; Nine floral designs (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Brochure, Watkins Brothers, 190-?; Brochure with "Banquet Toasts." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, J.S. Watson, 185-?; Successor to C. H. Webster (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Waverley Restaurant, 18--?; J. Earle Duley, Proprietor (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Envelope, Henry R. Way, 190-?; "Tobacco bought and sold on commission" (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Weatherby, Knous and Pelton, 186-? (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Webb Brothers, 1881; Two humorous designs copyrighted by the Calvert Lith. Co. Detroit in 1881. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Weed Sewing Machine Company, 187-?; "Our Mamas All Have a 'Hartford' Sewing Machine." Printed by The Kellogg & Bulkeley Company, Hartford. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, A.P. Weeks, 1881?; Design with child and flowers (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, T.C. Weildon, 185-?; "Inventor and Only Manufacturer of Spider Web Wigs." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Robert Weller Wine and Lager Beer Saloon and Restaurant, 187-?; Four different designs (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, B.F. Welles and Company, 185-?; "Choice Goods and Low Prices for Cash a Specialty." Partners are B. F. Welles and C. L. Smith. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, James G. Welles and Company, 188-?; One floral design (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, James G. Welles and Company, 188-?; "A Lost Art Restored!! Egyptian Te-Nex-Ine, The Most Powerful Adhesive Known..." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, E.D. Wells, 185-?; "All orders for the above promptly attended to, and packed and sent to any part of the City, Boats or Cars, free of expense." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, N.G. West, 187-?; One floral design (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Conrad Whitmore, 185-?; "All kinds of Copper Work made and repaired. Stills made and repaired. Babbitt Metal and Rivets of all descriptions." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, W.F. Whittelsey and Company, 187-?; Two different designs (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Business card, Wholesale Waterbeds, 1991; Business card of Ilene Kaufman ("Bob" written in). (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, M. Wieder, 187-?; "I also inform my friends that I buy all my live stock and vegetables for cash." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Brochure, Wilcox and Maxham, 188-?; Two brochures: "We are constantly receiving fine Artistic Pottery and Glass Ware from All Countries… " (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Alfred Williams, 187-?; "Re-coloring of Seal Sacques a Specialty." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, E.D. Williams, 187-?; One design featuring a winter scene (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Williams and Carleton Company, 1897; One cut-out and embossed card featuring three boys with coffee cups (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade cards, Williams and Carleton Company, 188-?; Three cards advertising Williams' Blood Purifier. "If you do not feel absolutely well and strong, you should take Williams' Blood Purifier immediately…. " (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade cards, Williams and Carleton Company, 188-?; Three cards advertising Williams' New England Cough Remedy. "It is very pleasant to take, contains no opium in any form and is perfectly harmless, and at the same time very effectual in 'breaking up' Colds and Coughs." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade cards, Williams and Carleton Company, 189-?-190-?; Six cards advertising Williams' Root Beer Extract and Williams' Root Beer, "The Great Family Drink." Three cards printed by The Kellogg & Bulkeley Co., Hartford (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Postcard, Williams and Carleton Company, 1908; Postcard with picture of a bottle of Root Beer Extract. Card is adddressed to E. C. Dickenson Company in Essex, Connecticut and is an order for birch oil. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Notebook, Willis and Wilson, 190-?; "We Sell the Famous Hart Schaffner & Marx Clothing." Blank book with advertising on front and back covers. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Coupon, Wise, Smith and company, 1901; "This Coupon entitles the holder to an Artistic Life Like Crayon Portrait… " (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Brochure, Wise, Smith and company, 191-?; Brochure advertising the Macey Sectional Bookcase (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Postcard, Witkower's, 1945; Postcard advertising "A. Woollcott: His Life and His World." "Due to wartime paper difficulties, our supply of this book will be limited for some time." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Bookmark, Witkower's, 193-?; "Booksellers since 1835." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, O.D. Woodruff and Company, 1979?; Partners are O. D. Woodruff and J. E. Woodruff. Two different romantic designs. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, Woodruff and Beach Iron Works, 1867; 1867 calendar on the back. "Builders of Engines in the U.S. Steam Sloops of War 'Mohican', 'Kearsarge', 'Piscataqua', 'Minnesota', and 'Manitou'; and the U. S. Gunboats 'Cayuga', 'Pequot' and 'Nipsic…" (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, J.C. Woods and Company, 188-?; One card with poem advertising Wilcox & White organs (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Brochure, J.C. Woods and Company, 189-?; Brochure listing merchandise available (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Trade card, J.C. Wooley and Company, 190-?; Design features a woman pushing a lawn mower with one hand. (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Postcard, Wright's Souvenir Postal Cards, 190-?; George E. Wright, Proprietor. "Souvenir Postal Cards Manufactured on Orders from a Distance. Pictures Taken, Cuts Made, Cards Printed and Delivered." (Box 10, Folder W)
  - Postcard, A.W. Yates, 191-?; Alva B. Yates, Proprietor. "Time Means Honey for Me." (Box 10, Folder Y)
  - Trade card, Henry J. Zweygartt, 186-?; "Dealer in all kinds of Imported Havana, and manufacturer of Domestic Cigars." (Box 10, Folder Z)
  - Advertisement, Alderman Drug Company, 193-?; Cut out "Miles Weather Chart" with advertisement for Alka-Seltzer (Box 11)
  - Brochure, Alderman Drug Company, 190-?; Brochure "Feminine Shoeprints of the Ages" features the "Walk-Over Shoe" (Box 11)
  - Bookmark, R. Ballerstein and Company, 188-?; Four different designs featuring landscapes (Box 11)
  - Bookmark, Becher and Eitel, 193-?; "30 years of experience at your service." (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, The Beehive, 188-?; Image of Santa Claus on front, Bee-Hive Carol on back. Printed by The Kellogg & Bulkeley Co. (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, Central Stationery Company, 195-?; Advertisement for Keeboard Typewriter Papers (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, George E. Dewey and Company, 194-?; "Let Dewey Do It." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Theodore Clark, 189-?; Two cards with view of Mount Hood, Oregon, with Clark's name and address added with a rubber stamp in different locations (Box 11)
  - Rack card, Conning and Company, 1929; Partners are W. S. Conning, W. C. Goeben, C. T. Treadway, J.D. Britton and D. R. Griswold. Card is dated February 13, 1929. (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Fairman and Henry, 188-?; Successors to Fairman & Miller. (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Bruce Filley and Company, 1894; Quaker Ranges, "Queen of the Kitchen." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Fisk's Popular Shoe Store, 1885; Card with picture of a young woman, inscribed "Given away with shoes at Fisk's Popular Shoe Store." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, A.L. Foster and Company, 189-; Nine different cards with different designs in different formats (Box 11)
  - Label, Ralph R. Foster, 1861; Label for "Pure Ground Mustard Prepared by Ralph R. Foster" (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Fowler and San Souci, 188-; Two different designs (Box 11)
  - Rack card, A. Freedman, 192-?; Tailoring, Cleaning, Dyeing, Pressing and Repairing. (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Gemmill, Burnham and Company, 188-?; One design featuring an easel, a horseshoe, and a ship (Box 11)
  - Postcard, Hartford Despatch, 1981; Postcard featuring moving vans in front of Hartford skyline (Box 11)
  - Trade card, J.P. Haynes, 188-?; "Wishing you a blithe and peaceful Christmas." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, E.S. Kendall and Company, Hub Clothing House, 188-?; Seven different designs (Box 11)
  - Trade card, J.H. Otis, 189-?; Card with picture of a woman, "Compliments of J. H. Otis…." (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, C.A. Pitkin, 1873; Image of "White Leghorns. Bred by C. A. Pitkin, Hartford, Conn." Printed by Kellogg and Bulkeley (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, William H. Post Carpet Company, 191-?; "However much we esteem our Friendships we do not ask or expect Patronage as a Favor." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, George O. Sawyer, 189-; Card with picture of a woman, "Compliments of George O. Sawyer" (Box 11)
  - Advertisement, Talcott and Frisbie, 188-; Card with advertisement for Dr. Thomas' Eclectic Oil. (Box 11)
  - Trade card, A. Wakefield and Company, 191-?; Card with picture of a woman, "Compliments of A. Wakefield & Co." (Box 11)
  - Trade card, William Wander and Son, 188-?; Image of women in an interior with a Decker Brothers piano (Box 11)
  - Trade card, W.F. Whittelsey and Company, 188-?; Two different designs, one a cut-out in the shape of a standing bear (Box 11)
  - Trade card, I.M. Wilcox, 188-?; Card with picture of a girl, "Compliments of I. M. Wilcox…" (Box 11)
  - Trade card, I.M. Wilcox, 189-?; Card with picture of two Japanese women (Box 11)
  - Trade card, Witkower's, 194-?; Two different designs, one inscribed "Buy War Bonds and Stamps." (Box 11)